Cobain: Montage of Heck is a documentary, music,
drama film directed by Brett Morgen.
Hailed as one of the most innovative and intimate documentaries of all time, experience Kurt Cobain
like never before in the only ever fully authorized portrait of the famed music icon.
Academy Award nominated filmmaker Brett Morgen expertly blends Cobain's personal archive of art, music, never
seen before movies, animation and revelatory interviews from his family and closest friends.
Self (archive footage), played by Kurt Cobain.
Self, played by Courtney Love.
Self, played by Krist Novoselic.
Self (archive footage), played by Dave Grohl.
Self (archive footage), played by Frances Bean Cobain.
Self (archive footage), played by Pat Smear.
Kurt Cobain: Montage of Heck is a 2015 American documentary
film about Nirvana lead singer Kurt Cobain.
The film was directed by Brett Morgen and premiered
at the 2015 Sundance Film Festival.
It received a limited theatrical release worldwide and premiered on
television in the United States on HBO on May 4, 2015.
The documentary chronicles the life of Kurt Cobain from his birth in Aberdeen, Washington, in 1967, through his troubled early family life
and teenage years and rise to fame as frontman of Nirvana, up to his suicide in April 1994 in Seattle at the age of 27.
The film includes artwork by Cobain as well as music
and sound collages composed by him.
Much of the music and sound collages were released on the film's
soundtrack, Montage of Heck: The Home Recordings.
A companion book was also released containing film animation stills from the film as well as
transcripts of interviews, photographs, and pieces of Cobain's artwork not featured in the film.
The film explores themes of drug abuse, musician,
rock star, lifestyle, drug addiction.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.